L.A.C. Dat Instruments。
The LAC rules.
我 wish to give a brief account of the work of the Bills Committee.
內地税收條例修訂第6條第2018。
which commenced operation in December two thousand and eight.
主席，喺我嘅職能係作為法案委員會主席。
Their hybrid nature raises questions about their tax treatment.
in particular, whether they are eligible for debt-like tax treatment under IRO.
The bill amends the inland revenue cap one one two to provide debt-like tax treatment for loss-absorbing capacity.
In order to meet the external or internal lack requirements prescribed by rules.
The main objective of the bill is to provide certainty of tax treatment for lack debt instrument.
In order to facilitate the implementation of the financial institutions resolution laws or setting capacity requirements, banking set rules.
while the legal form of debt instruments is debt-like, such instruments have an equity-like loss-absorbing feature.
under the LAC rules, authorised institutions, their holding companies or affiliated operational entities are required to issue LAC debt instruments.
such instruments can be written down or converted into equity to absorb losses of an entity and hence recapitalising the entity when it becomes non-viable and goes into resolution.
個二零一八年財務彙報局修訂條例草案，本會恢復二零一八年税務修訂第六號條例草案嘅二讀辯論。條例草案委員會主席梁繼昌議員會先就委員會報告向本會發言。梁繼昌議員。
back-to-back transactions.
through holding that instruments issued by other AIs.
may be induced by the proposed tax deduction and stamp duty exemption.
for intra-group transactions which involve back-to-back arrangements.
There are also concerns that an AI which is still viable.
to abuse the use of resolution, so as to obtain capital resources.
in particular, for transactions between a subsidiary and its holding company, that is.
所以，佢哋會係合資格嘅，對於利息開支減免，對於profits tax目的。
立法會委員會已舉行一次會議，研究該法案，並收到兩份有關該法案的提交。
The purchaser of internal lack instruments that is a holding company, has to meet external lack requirements of his own.
如果控股公司或主要附屬公司購置外部債券發行由其他銀行集團發行的債券，
Some members of the bills committee have expressed concern on whether AIs can utilise various financial arrangements, for instance.
The administration has advised that the lack rules have prescribed restrictions on the sale and holding of lack instruments by AIs.
The holding company's holdings of internal lack instruments issued by the material subsidiary need to be deducted from its resources for meeting its external lack requirements.
或 purchasing debt instruments issued by a subsidiary in the same banking group in order to exploit the proposed profits tax deduction and stamp duty exemption。
The definition of regulatory capital securities under IRO is expanded to include lack debt instrument, so that the transfer of lack debt instruments will be exempt from stamp duty under the stamp duty ordinance, Cap 117.
which possess features of both debt and equity.
deal at arm's length in connection with RCF.
are treated as debts by the international financial community.
它 has to make a corresponding reduction in its own capital.
In particular, if the holding company is not chargeable to tax in Hong Kong.
利息 payable by the AI will be allowable for deduction.
The basic rule is that the AI will not be eligible for interest deduction.
但係，amount of deduction會被Restricted to the sum payable by the holding company to a third party.
The bill seeks to amend the definition of RCS in IRO to reflect this international practice.
議事委員會已探討關於減免轉移缺乏債券的税項的原因。
The administration has explained that RCS， consisting of additional tier one capital instruments， and tier two capital instruments and other lack debt instruments。
regarding back-to-back transactions，the administration has explained the rules for interest，the expenses deduction that will apply if an AI issues internal debt instruments to its holding company。
The deduction in lag capital prevents holding companies and AIs from artificially increasing their capital through holding of lag instruments issued by their group companies or other banking groups.
however，if the holding company's funding for the purchase of the AI's internal lack debt instruments is from the issuance of external lack debt instrument， or other debt instruments to a third party，
the bills committee has inquired whether the bill includes anti avoidance provisions on interest expenses deductions concerning back to back transactions and transactions between an AI or a lack banking entity and its associates.
As regards transactions between an AI or a lack banking entity and its associates, the administration has advised that anti-avoidance measures are prescribed in Section 17E of IRO, which says out how profits shall be adjusted if the associates do not.
嗰個啊！
吸吸收虧損型債務票據嗰個誒？
The amendment in the bill will extend the stamp duty exemption to all lack debt instruments.
嚇債務票據嘅買賣，亦都係係啊納入印花税嘅豁免嘅範圍。
喺早之前咧，呢條嘅條例草案啊，係税務啦。當然之前咧，嗰個債務。
the bills committee has no objection to resuming the second reading debate on the bill, and will not propose amendments to the bill.
喺確定應課税利用時咧，係容許扣減某些實體就監管資本證券而借入嘅金錢嘅利息。
將某些實體所收取或者累算歸於該等實體嘅某些款項咧，當作係營業收入，即係要畀利得税啦。
太多分行嘅銀行，而嗰個啊資產嘅誒總值都非常之低嘅銀行，究竟需唔需要咧？係去啊完全去符合呢一個啊？
Currently, transfer of RCS covering additional tier one and tier two capital requirements, which are already treated as debt securities, is exempt from stamp duty.
咁呢條條例草案嘅目的咧，係將一啲某些吸收虧損能力嘅債務票據咧，就利得税而言咧，係視為債務證券，即係話debt instrument。
誒主席閣下，呢一條啊條例草案其實一個非常之技術嘅税務修訂條例啦。咁呢個都係即係二零一八年到嘅第六條條例草案。即係可想言之，我哋作為一個國際金融中心，其實係與時並進嘅。
規定某一啲實體冇資格成為合格資格嘅企業財資中心，就並其他嘅事宜咧係作出修訂，包括咧係將一啲嘅啊虧損能力債務票據咧嘅交易買賣咧係豁免印花税，因為眾所周知啦。
係完全唔會有效嘅。
嗱，呢啲噉嘅誒。
嘅誒工具嘅。
但係問題咧，呢一啲嘅。
呢度個問題就係啲leg instrument，如果，
作出嘅一個嘅啊，税務啊條例嘅修訂。
誒，我哋嘅意見咧，啊，因而咧，啊，好多嘅比較啊細嘅。
咁據税務局嘅解釋咧，因為條條例草案未通過咧，佢係唔會有呢一個嘅利息税務扣減嘅。
一個假設嘅情況就係話：喂，如果啲銀行無端端喺呢條條例草案通過之前咧，已經發行咗呢啲let instrument咧。
税務票嘅本身個性質喺條例通過之前或者之後咧，都係冇變過嘅嗰個即係性質，完全係嗰都係嗰樣嘢嚟嘅。
咁呢啲工具當然喺平時嚟講係好似債務，但係一啲咩事發生嘅時候咧，佢可以將佢轉換成為呢個誒資本嘅。咁點解要轉換咧？就因為其中一個原因咧，就喺呢一度指出就可以吸收一啲虧損。
subsidiary legislation咧嗰個誒附屬法例咧，其實喺誒十月十二號嗰陣時嘅立法會咧，亦都係誒誒通過咗一個係依個，因為咧係個誒誒並非個主體法例，只不過我哋係係係追補翻係通過咗，而當然咧。
附屬法例所引起嘅爭議就係話，如果我哋要消除啊國際銀行體係之間嘅一啲嘅系統性嘅風險，究竟一啲比較中小型嘅銀行，尤其是個經營業務範圍咧，只係喺香港或者本地啊，或者喺海外係又誒唔係？
發行呢個啊吸收虧損能力債務票據呢一個嘅國際嘅一個準則咧，咁其實喺該一次嘅啊小組委員會嘅小組討論入邊咧，我哋亦都係向政府咧係提議咗好多嘅建議，而政府亦都係啊大部分採納咗嘅。
中小型銀行咧係並不需要咧係誒要發出呢一啲嘅票據。其實咧，即係主席，你都知道，如果太多銀行喺同一時間咧發出呢啲票據嘅時候咧，其實喺市場上，無論係本地市場好啦，或者國際市場都好咧，其實係好難吸收曬或者買曬。
呢一啲嘅票據，因為呢啲票據發出咗之後咧，係必須要由即係銀行體係以外嘅一啲嘅金融機構買咗呢啲票據咧，呢一啲嘅防震作用、呢啲吸收虧損能力作用咧，先正可以生效嘅。如果你銀行同銀行之間買翻咧，根本呢一個嘅啊減低風險嘅作用咧，或者減低系統風險作用。
咁由於嗰個條例誒附屬條例係啊喺小組嗰度討論咗，亦都喺立法會度通過咗啦。噉啊呢一條嘅税務修訂條例組，我亦都係相應翻該一個嘅誒附屬法例嘅一啲嘅誒虧損吸收能力票據咧，係而做嘅一齣誒。
咁但係咧，技術上咧，我亦都有一個嘅疑問嘅，因為咧有一啲嘅委員或者有啲嘅啊業界嘅朋友問到，好多時銀行都好多時咧係會發出一啲又好似係債務票據嘅，又好似係啲資本嘅，即係一啲混合體嘅一啲嘅。
但係。
都係主席。
我跟住發言。
喺呢條財委草案通過之前咧，佢都係一個既係好似。
因為佢嘅性質唔會係因為呢一個嘅啊。
嗱，本條例草案嘅目的咧，主要係處理金融機構。
嘅誒條例草案係支持呢個條例草案嘅恢復二讀啊，同埋啊三讀嘅。
只不過呢個條例草案通過咗之後咧，嗰個税務嘅處理會變得清晰咗。
債券亦都嘅係好似一個資本嘅一啲個債務票一個票據，咁冇理由。
冇理由係唔畀即係税務扣減畀佢嘅喎。嗱，如果佢真係啊正正經經發行咗。
條例通過咗而改變㗎嘛？只不過呢條條例係即係畀咗一個比較清晰嘅確認佢啫嘛。之前佢都係有一個債務票據嘅一個性質嘅特性喺度㗎啦。
噉我就唔明啦，點解會係噉樣樣咧？因為我記得喺幾年前，我哋處理緊一啲嘅都係同一個誒銀行有關嘅資本結構嘅時候咧，當時咧。
税務局係畀咗一啲特別嘅安排，畀呢啲既係啊債務票據，又係資本嘅一啲嘅票據，一啲特別嘅處理喺個條例未通過之前咧，佢係特別咧係寬容，係畀一個利息扣減嘅。
咁呢個嘅做法究竟係咪可以以後啊都可以跟隨呢？即係如果未有呢個實際嘅啊法例通過之前，係咪呢一類噉嘅票據都可能有一個啊特別嘅處理呢？
混合形式嘅票據咧，其實嗰個誒税務安排喺以往都唔係話誒好清楚嘅。喺大概三四年前，我都記得有一條嘅條税務修訂條例草案係將一個嘅誒呢一類型嘅混合式嘅誒債務票據咧，係畀咗一個税務嘅寬免出嚟。
即係LAC啦。
呢個有一定嘅影響力嘅。
的確係具有穩定作用嘅。
所引申嘅税務條例嘅問題。
其他合資格嘅LAC負責。
噉啊，有關係維持最低吸收虧損能力。
呢啲金融機構為咗維持最低嘅OAC。
喺呢個條例裏面咧，有一啲誒對香港金融體係。
即係處置機處置機制吸收虧損能力，銀行界嘅規定。
噉啊，最後尾三者咧就一一般都我哋叫做LACP債務票據啦。
誒，似乎都幾複雜下，即係如果唔係話誒學內人士咧，對呢啲都唔係咁清楚嘅。
作為LAC嘅債務票據，其中合資格嘅LAC負債咧，喺現時嘅税務條例。
誒呢個同額外嘅一般嘅額外嘅一級誒資本票據同埋額外嘅二級資本票據嘅税務定義咧，係睇齊嘅。
噉啊！我哋都知道咧，必須係要維持最低嘅LAC嘅，以避免呢啲金融機構咧一旦出現營運問題咧，對香港金融體係造成衝擊同埋振盪。
即係最低嘅吸收虧損能力啦，啊，必須要發行呢個有關LAC嘅票據。呢啲LAC票據咧，包括係監管資本嘅票據啦、額外嘅一級資本票據啦、額外嘅二級資本票據啦，及其。
裡面啊，並嗰個界定並不清晰嘅，因此咧，本條例草案喺界定呢啲合資格嘅LAC負債税務地位嚟講咧，就將佢哋合資格嘅LAC負債就利得税嘅層面睇為誒負債證券。
咁除咗利得税嘅利息扣減之外，咁印花税亦都有產生同樣嘅問題。咁可能即係局長，可能今日都未必可以處理到呢個問題。但我希望啊，局方咧喺之後咧係會就一啲時間上，究竟喺邊個時刻先至可以攞到呢啲税務嘅扣減同。
埋啊！實際上係幾時可以攞去扣減咧？呢啲問題咧係即係喺以以後嘅一啲啊比較新嘅一啲票據或者啲誒金融工具咧，係思考一下啊！主席，我今次發言，我睇唔到有任何理由呢個嗯會嘅同事咧係係要反對呢一個嘅。
主席。
穩定咧係有重要嘅幫助嘅。
如果冇，現在請局長答辯，之後辯論即告結束。財經事務及庫務局局長。
困仍然有資源吸收虧損同埋資本重組，以助進行有秩序嘅處置。
逃税嘅，因此，嗯，我同民建聯咧，誒都會支持呢個條例草案嘅。多謝主席。是否有其他委員想議員想發言？
票據，以及三由喺香港以外成立違法團嘅認可機構，根據某非香港司法管轄區嘅相應嘅leg規定所發行嘅所有票據。
首先，我要感謝二零一八年税務修訂第六號條例草案法案委員會主席梁繼昌議員同埋各位委員嘅審議工作。自從金融機構處置機制條例
為咗達到税務對稱，相關實體就叻嘅債務票據所得或者累算嘅利息收益或者利潤，需要被當作係營業收入並被納入應課利得税嘅涵蓋範圍之內。
為咗配合規則嘅落實，條例草案再有條文定明由認可機構同埋佢相關嘅集團公司發行嘅LEK嘅債務票據嘅税務待遇，有關修訂會將所有LEK嘅債務票據嘅税務待遇。
誒，我哋而家係計劃豁免徵收轉讓呢啲LAC債務票據嘅印花税。就此咧，我同埋民建聯認為啊，本條例草案嘅主旨咧係喺完成處置條例對香港維護香港嘅金融市場穩。
誒，而且當局喺條例中咧，誒，亦都會有一啲措施係防止金融機構啊，係利用各種呢個誒最低吸收負誒虧損能力，即係呢個LAC嘅債務票據嘅税務優惠咧，係進行。
嘅主要條文喺二零一七年七月生效以嚟，各處置機制當局一直致力提升金融機構嘅處置可行性，以其確保金融穩定。其中，金融管理專員作為銀行界實體嘅處置機制當局，已經喺去年。
同埋二級資本票據嘅豁免印花税待遇，延伸至所有leck嘅債務票據。最後，我感謝小組委員會主席條例草案。
反對嘅請舉手。我認為議題係獲得在席議員以過半數贊成，我宣佈議案獲得通過。二零一八年税務修訂第六號條例草案會唔會成為？
畀規則能夠順利完落實，促進金融穩定，鞏固香港作為國際金融中心嘅地位。主席，我僅此陳謝。多謝。現在嘅代議議題係二零一八年税務修訂第六號條例草案，與議議讀，贊成嘅請舉手。
年十二月，根據處置條例第十九括弧一條，緊貼金融穩定理事會於總吸收虧損能力細則清單裏邊所載關於吸收虧損能力規定嘅國際標準，制定咗金融機構處置機制。
吸收虧損能力規定銀行界嘅規則，就銀行同埋佢個集團公司訂立關乎最低吸收虧損能力，即係LEAK嘅規定，要求某些銀行需要維持最低水平嘅LEAK。一旦該等銀行陷入財，
與根據監管資本制度發行嘅額外一級資本票據同埋二級資本票據嘅税務待遇係會睇齊。根據建議嘅修訂，就利得税而言，下列票據將會被視作債務嚟處理。第一係由認可機構發行嘅咧。
嘅債務票據現已享有類似債務嘅税務待遇嘅額外一級資本票據同埋二級資本票據除外。第二，由認可機構嘅商連營運實體或者純控控權公司發行嘅所有債嘅債務票。
法案委員會成員曾經就條例草案會否被濫用作避税用途表示關注，就此我哋確認條例草案中已經再有相關嘅防止避税條文。此外，條例草案亦都會使現時適用於轉讓額外一級資本票據。